Right now in our application we are able to navigate around,
u anda bavurumuzda gezinebilmekteyiz.
We are able to do that without reloading the page.
Sayfay yeniden yklemeden bunu yapabiliyoruz.
Now let's have a look at the information we actually get in the components we're loading because react
imdi, yklemeye ynelik bileenlerde elde ettiimiz bilgilere bir gz atalm nk yeniden
router gives us some extra information about the loaded route through props.
ynlendirici ynlendirici, ykl roud meyve sahas hakknda bize ek bilgi verir.
Let's have a look at posts, there in componentDidMount which will be executed each time we changed a page
Bileeni gerekten de kaldrld ve DOM'a her zaman eklendii iin bir
because the component is really removed and added to the DOM all the time.
sayfay deitirdiimizde yrtlecek olan Da'nda bulunan yazlara bakalm.
There we not only reach out to the web,
Orada yalnzca Web'e ulamakla kalmyoruz.
let's also output the props we have by simply outputting these props.
Sahip olduumuz sahne takmlarn da sadece bu sahne koyarak kalm.
Now let's have a look at what we got here,
imdi burada ne var bir gz atalm.
if I go to home now, this is the props object and history, location and match,
imdi eve felaket sahne nesne ve gemii konum ve ma giderseniz.
this is not something we set up,
Bu, kurduumuz bir ey deil.
this is passed by react router.
Bu, tekrar aktr ynlendirici tarafndan iletilir.
Now match
Eleme yok.
gives us some information about the matched route, you saw that we defined it to be exact the path and
Bize kurabileceiniz kuraklk hakknda kesin bilgi vermek iin yol gsterici olduumuzu ve bu nedenle bulduunuz
URL are found therefore and potential params, I'll come back to what params are later.
ve potansiyel ebeveynlerin hepsinin ebeveynlerin daha sonra neler olduunu greceiniz hakknda bilgi verin.
You get more information about the location and there you see for example the search
Bulunduunuz yer hakknda daha fazla bilgi edinin ve rnein arama yapmaya cesaret edersiniz.
params we set up or something like that at the hash fragment and the history. The history object also
Hazrladmz ebeveynler ya da buna benzer bir ey ve karma para ve tarihin gemii Optik,
has some methods we can use like push to interact with that and push a new page programmatically without
bununla etkileime girmek ve bir link bileene ihtiya duymadan programl bir ekilde yeni bir sayfa basmak gibi kullanabileceimiz
needing a link component,
baz yntemlere sahiptir.
this is also something I will show you later.
Bunlarn hepsi daha sonra gstereceim bir ey.
Now let's go back to our components and let's also log the props in the new post,
imdi paralarmza geri dnelim ve sahteleri de yeni yaynda kilitleyelim.
there we also therefore can add componentDidMount and inside there,
Orada da bileen ekleyebiliriz, burada montaj ve igr var.
I now also want to output the props because there we should see more information regarding the fragment
Para ve arama parantezleri ile ilgili daha fazla bilgi grmeliyiz nk sahteleri
and the search params.
de kartmak istiyorum.
So let's click on new post and inspect the props there and now you'll see under match the path we found there,
Bu yzden yeni yaynlar tklayn ve Propst'i inceleyin ve imdi orada bulduumuz yolu eletirelim.
you see that it also is exact match.
Ayn zamanda tam bir eleme olduunu da gryorsunuz.
Now we didn't set up exact matching here,
imdi burada tam eleme oluturmadk.
we don't have the exact option but we are on new post.
Kesin seenee sahip deiliz, ancak yeni grev yapyoruz.
If I were on new post 2, I added this manually. It would still render this because we didn't set up exact
Bunu el ile eklediim yeni yaynda olsaydm bunu hala gerekletirebilirdik, nk tam
matching but it would also see that we don't have an exact match in the match property.
eleme oluturmadysak da eleme mlknde tam bir eleme olmadn greceksiniz.
So this really tells us is the full URL the full path,
Dolaysyla bu gerekten tam yolun tam olduunu bize syler.
the path we set up in the config or not? We also got more information on the location.
atmaya kurduumuz yol ya da deil, konum hakknda daha fazla bilgi var.
You'll see the search addition you added at the end and you could manually parse this to retrieve the
Sonunda eklediiniz bu aramay greceksiniz ve sorgu parantezlerini almak iin bunu manuel
query params
olarak ayrtrabilirsiniz.
and you see your hash fragment too which you could then also use to jump to a certain part of your page or
Ve sayfanzn belirli bir blmne atlamak iin kullanabileceiniz karma paracklarnz ya da
as smoothly scroll there whatever you want.
istediiniz yerde kaydrarak sorunsuzca kaydrdnz gryorsunuz.
So this is some additional information we get,
Bu, aldmz baz ek bilgi.
this is part of the props and you can use that to for example extract your query params, move to
Bu sahne blmnn bir parasdr ve bunu, rnein, dutlu ebeveynlerini kark bir paraya ayklamak iin
a hash fragment or do whatever else you need to do.
kullanabilir veya yapmanz gereken her eyi yapabilirsiniz.
We will later see how we used this history object to use a method that provides us.
Daha sonra, bu gemi nesnesini bize salayan bir yntem kullanmak iin nasl kullandmz greceiz.